<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Leon's blog</title><link href="http://domuse.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://domuse.com/feeds/pyhtonbian-cheng.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://domuse.com/</id><updated>2015-08-24T00:00:00+08:00</updated><entry><title>Data Preview v0.1 released</title><link href="http://domuse.com/data-preview-release.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-08-24T00:00:00+08:00</published><author><name>Leon</name></author><id>tag:domuse.com,2015-08-24:data-preview-release.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Data Preview is a simple Python GUI program (using tkinter at present, maybe PyQt in the next version) to automatically convert the experimental data (just tsv format in this version) to graph by clicking the filename. A set of data files can also be simply merged together into a single data file with the selected data columns (i.e. variables). The data preprocess function has been proposed to be enhanced in the following release.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This program is a experimental project launched in last week. Our target is to avoid the time-consuming and repeating work on the preview and preprocess of data generated by the instrument in our lab. By employing the easy-to-use Python language, I finished the first primitive version in three days without any GUI programing experience before. At this stage, the Data Preview with simple functions has been put to use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Features:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Preview tsv data automatically or manully (click the 'Plot Show' popon with matplotlib builtin figure dialog) allowing to select data column&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fast merge datafiles with specific variables&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dependencies:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;pandas&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;matplotlib&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PIL (NOTE: install image other than Pillow)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Open source in Github: to be coming...&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="python"></category><category term="GUI"></category></entry></feed>